good morning
i do what i always do which you're not
supposed to do i just grab your phone
first thing in the morning i mainly grab
it to see what time it is and then get
sucked into social media
and one of my facebook friends posted
this and then i posted a response and
that is what this video is about
the revelation is that there is just two
basic economic states
communism on and communism off when
there is capitalism off
when there is capitalism off goes the
communism
remove the capitalism and only communism
remains communism is the origin state
and the destiny state and capitalism is
just a phase in between
it takes great energy to keep capitalism
on it's a real waste because capitalism
is not very economical it's a tragedy
because capitalism is expensive toxic
extremely unhealthy and brutally
destructive
it can be this simple mathematical and
predictable we can
we want a certain mathematical quality
in the future language
and the key is not being disappointed as
much as to maximize predictability
my statement which is what i'm going to
talk about today is capitalism can be
thought of as massive
state-led competition and communism is
massively
state-run cooperation both are massive
and not voluntary if you turn off
complicated capitalism
you do not get communism nor should you
creating what it is you desire is about
individuals having i don't think i made
sense when i said that
it's about individuals so what he's
basically stating what i'm assuming he's
stating in his pose
is if we just didn't have capitalism
we'd have beautiful beautiful communism
and i think no
no we would not because i have yet to
hear
anyone have a beautiful vision of the
future that doesn't doesn't require
enforcing that
with violence on the rest of the
population
and so to me the difference isn't
state-run
cooperation or state-run competition
because either way you're going to have
people that want to do the other one
and aren't allowed so if you have it be
that you just switch from
forced competition to force cooperation
it's forced and it's not gonna work
whereas creating something that is
voluntary cooperation where people can
see what they truly get out of
cooperation
not communism where people
one we see historically what happens but
you have a tiny group of people
who are at least to the beginning
running it and saying what quotas are
telling you what your job is telling you
all these things which are still a
hierarchy down structure
there and therefore there's a lot of
tension there
and even if that tension is
theoretically gone from
what is best for the individual creating
the rules
and or capitalism to
creating a world that is in
supposed to be in benefit of all because
you're still going to do it for yourself
first of all
and um it's going to be
as opposed to politicians pretending
they're doing it for their constituents
to central planners pretending to do it
for the good of society
they're still going to be working in
their own best self-interest
i do think there's something to what
he's saying that we did go through
a more cooperative version of history
mainly tribalism
um that some people are still living in
that is
um living off the lens
working within the ecosystem you know
your neighbors
generally you don't kick people out
except in extreme circumstances
and you're making sure everyone's needs
are looked after everyone's contributing
everyone's getting their needs looked
after but when you get
bigger and more complex in society and
you have a agriculture which of course
in tribal societies have agriculture
having um once we started on a mass
scale having agriculture
and expanding and colonization happened
all
over the globe might equal right and gun
germs and steel spread competition
everywhere and if you weren't willing
not only you could you say actually no
we're good we're just going to cooperate
over here
um if you weren't up to snuff in
competition you were just annihilated
and i hate to say that's a necessary
step for us to have gone through because
it's all the shitty shitty things humans
have done to each other
in the last few centuries millennia and
yet
yeah we're still there we still need
other people to listen to me and do it
my way
and that doesn't get us communism or
capitalism
what we need is a voluntary
cooperation and it out competes
capitalism it
out competes mandatory competition and
voluntary competition
on a massive scale because who are you
gonna choose
a company whose product is there to make
the person who created it richer and
richer and richer or
a cooperative that's there to make sure
their employees have a decent wage but
is more there
to make sure that that product is safe
that it's efficient
that it lasts for a long time and that
the
consumer themselves like it because it's
a consumer cooperative because we have
the same incentive
we want a good product and so if we're
cooperating to do that
now if the government's the one creating
that widget the government's the one
creating
that product um they're setting a quota
and it's going to be
a shitty shitty product there's no say
and let's make it no it's good the state
made it
it's got to be good go line up for hours
to get it
whereas when we're all empowered with
the ability to create
tools and we can create them
competitively and we can create them
with
cooperation cooperation is just going to
win every time so if you want a winning
product
you're going to choose cooperation and
figure out how to get your
competitiveness out in other ways that
doesn't mean zero competition doesn't
mean outlying competition
it just means you're not going to have a
proprietary monopoly
in a system that is demanding
transparency and cooperation
not demanding it under the law you're in
prison and you're not allowed to do it
just like right we're not gonna buy from
you
thanks your thing's more expensive and
you're destroying the planet
and you're not looking after your
workers we're gonna choose this one
especially the more empowered we are
and we don't have money ourselves and we
don't have empowerment over where we can
work and we are just in competition
it's hard to find our cooperative self
but it's the individuals cooperation
that we need and
it can be something that started with a
small group of people and grows because
if you create something
that is truly cooperative
it's omni-win everyone wins because
everyone's
saying everyone's needs are heard
whatever the solution is it has to take
all of the stakeholders into account
and if it's done in a way that is
transparent it's the only way for it to
be done
we trust it more there's just less money
going to wastage
like bureaucracy and like um
marketing and is going to actually
creating a better product and actually
going to pain people who are
detrimental is that right detrimental in
the supply chain the ones who are
absolutely needed
not the makeshift employment just so we
can say you have you have a job
that there is i mean you can go back and
listen to some of my old
videos i used words like communism i had
no
word for something like game b and so it
was like voluntary communism
technological socialism i don't know
what to call it
but those are the things that are going
to bring us forward the more
the people creating them can create them
for society and for other people even if
they themselves lose the faster we will
get there
the more that even in cooperation if the
individuals are in competition
and don't even know it won't even
necessarily acknowledge that and not
acknowledge that the feelings and
emotions that arise
then it'll take it'll take longer but
the more of us that are willing
to step into cooperation to truly
know that the better off you are
if we're in cooperation the better off i
am
when we're in competition the better off
you are the worse off i am
you can't play both of those games at
the same time
you know you can take a break from one
and play a board game and be in
competition and take a break from one
and you know play it soccer game and
be in competition but you can't
be in competition on the soccer field
and play your heart out
and worry about how the other person's
feelings are going to get hurt
that's not really that good so
i definitely want to keep this under 10
minutes my ipad was dying
so i came on stream yard to do a quick
live stream
to explain yeah i don't know if this
speaks to everyone else this morning but
it spoke to me as it was like you know
when you turn off capitalism you
definitely don't get communism
absolutely not but even bigger than that
it's not about
creating a new state we need a stateless
society
we need something that is fully
voluntary to each individual
and when since competition stops being
an option
you can't create a competitive amazon to
compete with our cooperative one
we already put the amazon out of
business when you know that happens in
two decades
um so what are you going to create
you can create something to be in
competition with your buddy right
i'm going to make a better coke i'm
gonna make a better a better uh
plate or table and if that brings you
joy that's fine but you can't start a
for-profit competition
because when we don't have patents
anyone can just
use it and you do it cooperatively and
you can't compete with cooperation
you just can't and so it eventually
leads to a massive cooperative on a
grand scale
when things are more official because
anyone can if a solution isn't working
for you
unlike under communism where what do you
mean it's not of course it's working for
you
it has to work it's communism shut up
shut up our gulags that we create
something that's
always able to be questioned but not
able to be questioned in an insufficient
way
right well this sucks great how do we
make it better i don't know but it sucks
well
perhaps you can offer something better
but
even if the food system isn't working
for you if you can think of a new way
and they're not willing to implement it
there's ways for you to implement it
to always have the option of creating
something better
which is like competition because you're
like i'm improving it this is better
then
that is a little bit competition and yet
because it's available to everyone
because it's sometimes not as easy as
something
always being better than something else
it's better than some
something that already existed to some
people
and so having as many options as
possible
as many governance structures as
possible so that we can try out what
works and what doesn't work what makes
us as individuals feel like we belong
and we're contributing and what makes us
feel like it's a big conglomerate
we can try out different systems we can
play at this
and get to competition or sorry
cooperation that we enjoy being part of
not forced cooperation by one tiny teams
this is how it should work and then
rolled out to everyone else and it's
enforced
but hey we all have a cooperative side
and we all have a competitive side
so how can we tap into your cooperative
side
and how can we tap into your competitive
side for good
and let's just keep moving towards that
as individuals
because when we create anything that's
scalable on that level
it's going to take over i'm on it
thanks for hanging out